It's a pleasure to be here
很高兴来到这里 2.
for today's W3C/SMPTE Joint Workshop
参加今天的W3C/SMPTE联合研讨会 3.
on professional media production on the web.
关于 web 上的专业媒体制作。 slide-2
This talk is about the principles of accessibility
这个演讲是关于无障碍方面的基本原则 5.
and driving accessibility into the creation of great tools
将无障碍融入到强大工具的创建中 6.
and apps and the web interfaces that are so critical
以及那些重要的应用程序和 web 的界面 7.
to their user experience and feature set. slide-2
对于他们的用户体验和功能设置方面 slide-3
I'm Ed Gray, I'm a proud 26-year veteran of Avid.
我是Ed Gray，我很骄傲是 Avid 公司26年的老员工
I'm the head of Avid's audio developer program,
我是 Avid 音频开发项目的负责人
and also director of accessibility for the company. 11-p
同时也是该公司的无障碍工作的主任 11-p
So I get to work with a bunch of talented,
所以我和一群才华横溢的人在一起工作
external and internal developers,
有来自外部和内部开发者
testers, customer support, and marketing people.
测试人员、客户支持和营销人员
And I'm also the main spokesman for accessibility,
我也是无障碍工作的主要代言人
so I organize and participate in a lot of panels
所以我组织并参加了很多讨论小组
like the ones that you see here. 17-p
就像你在这里看到的这些 17-p
I have a CPACC credential, which allows me to consult
我有一个 CPACC 证书，我可以向
to organizations on accessibility for their websites
机构组织询问他们网站上的无障碍相关问题
and stores and physical plant. 20-p
以及存储和具体的办公场地 20-p
And finally, I'm legally blind myself,
最后，从法律上讲，我自己也是盲人
so any accessibility goodness that we crank out,
所以我们所做的任何事情
I'll be the first in line to try it. slide-3
我都首当其冲去尝试体验 slide-4
Now, the business case for accessibility,
现在，关于无障碍情况例子
your tools and web interfaces is strong,
在你的工具和 web 界面中，很强大
but it's not always obvious,
但这并不总是很明显
just by looking at the market size.
只要看看市场规模
Now, the incidents of accessibility
现在，无障碍的存在
in developed countries is around 15%.
在发达国家，这一比例约为15%
And then zeroing in on visual impairments,
然后，针对视觉障碍
around three-quarters of percent
大约四分之三的比例
of people can't see the screen well enough
很多人看屏幕不够清楚
to do any reasonable work.
在做任何需要的工作时候
And another 3 to 4% can view the screen
还有另外 3-4% 看屏幕有些困难的人
with some difficulty with some visual aids. 35-p
需要用一些视觉辅助工具 35-p
So you can imagine that
所以你可以想象
if you're trying to justify a project based
如果你试图评价一个项目，基于
on that small portion of the population,
一小部分人
it's not always that easy to do.
做起来并不总是那么容易
But the important points to remember,
但要记住的重点是
that accessible innovation helps abled-users too.
这种无障碍的创新也有助于正常的用户
And that accessibility helps build your brand
并且，无障碍有助于建立你的品牌
and your reputation and creates goodwill
和你的声誉，还有营造好的商誉
and brings a lot of people to the media creation party. 44-p
会吸引很多人加入媒体创作团队 44-p
And finally, accessible development
最后是无障碍发展
is just development for usability for disabled persons.
这只是针对残疾人的实用性开发
And so accessible development can help you
因此，无障碍开发可以帮助你
uncover usability fixes and improvements
进行实用性问题修复和改进
that can benefit everyone. slide-4
这对每个人都有好处 slide-5
So let's talk about some principles and trends
让我们来谈谈一些基本原则和趋势
that you should keep in mind
大家应该记住
if you're becoming a student of accessibility.
如果你是一名无障碍的学生
And this gives me a chance to show
这就给我一个展示的机会
and to brag about my picture of Stevie Wonder.
还有可以吹嘘我拍的 Stevie Wonder 的照片的机会。
Here he is at the 2017 GRAMMY Awards,
这是他在2017年格莱美颁奖典礼上，
saying, make everything accessible for everyone,
他说，让每个人都可以无障碍获取所有内容，
everywhere in the world, no matter what disabilities.
在全世界，无论有什么障碍
And what he was speaking to
他想表达的意思是
is the principle of universal design.
是通用设计的原则
Universal design just means one tool for everybody,
通用设计是指每个人都可以使用的一种工具
instead of one version of the app for the blind users,
而不是为盲人用户提供的一个应用程序的版本
and another for the sighted folks,
另一个是给正常视力的人
and one version of your website for people
一个是为运动残障人士设计的网站
with motor disabilities, one without. 64-p
另一个则不是 64-p
You want one tool that people can all walk up to
你想要一个大家都可以使用的工具
and use in the same facility, in the same way.
并以同样的方式在同一设施中使用
And that's a very important guiding principle. 67-p
这是一个非常重要的指导原则 67-p
And accessibility is also legally driven
无障碍也是由法律驱动的
because whether or not it's wise or fair,
因为不管是否正确，或者为了公平
people are being hit with accessibility inquiries,
人们被无障碍问题所困扰
and sometimes lawsuits demanding
有时还需要起诉
that they improve the accessibility of their products.
他们提高了产品的无障碍特性
And as long as the company has a team committed
只要公司有一支致力于无障碍的团队
to accessibility, shows a record of accessible innovation,
有无障碍研发创新的记录
and a place to ask questions about accessibility,
和一个可以咨询无障碍问题的地方
they will be pretty well protected. 76-p
他们会得到很好的保障 76-p
Accessibility is also procurement driven,
无障碍也是由采购驱动的
meaning that in our space, in the media production space,
这意味着在我们的领域，在媒体制作方面，
there are schools and institutions
学校和机构
that won't consider committing to purchases
不会考虑去购买
unless you establish that your product
除非你确定你的产品
is decently accessible. 82-p
的确是无障碍的 82-p
That's usually done
通常情况是这样
with a Voluntary Product Accessibility Template,
有一个非强制的产品符合无障碍要求的表格
which is a document that you fill out independently
这是您自主填写的一个文档
that shows what features
这明确了一些特性
of your product meet, partially meet
你的产品符合，部分符合
and do not meet certain accessibility standards. 88-p
和不符合某些无障碍要求标准 88-p
And then finally, accessibility is external,
最后，无障碍是外来驱动的
beta tester and engineer driven.
是由测试人员和工程师驱动
So you don't want your accessibility features prioritized
就是，你不希望你的产品无障碍特性
and pursued by a group of empathetic, sighted engineers,
是由一群富有同情心、视力正常的工程师来研发
you want people with different disabilities giving input
应该是希望不同残疾的人群提供意见
and showing you how they work around real-world problems,
了解他们是如何面对存在的问题
they can help you prioritize fixes
他们可以帮助确认需要搞定的问题
in the most meaningful way. slide-5
以最有意义的方式 slide-6
The website front end to your application are tools
应用程序的网站前端是工具
like a mailbox at the foot of the driveway,
就像道路旁边的邮筒一样
gives you the impression of how it'll be used
给你一个如何使用它的印象
and what the overall experience will be like. 100-p
以及整体体验会是什么样子 100-p
So if it's not a winner for accessibility,
因此，如果它不是无障碍好的方面
it can be a killer, can render parts of the app invisible
它会是一个棘手的问题，可以使应用程序的某些部分不可见
or inaccessible by assisted devices
或无法被辅助设备访问
for people with motor challenges. 104-p
对有运动障碍的人来说 104-p
And so there's some tools that come to the rescue
所以有一些工具可以用来去补救
from the WCAG, the Web Content Accessibility Group,
来自WCAG，即Web内容无障碍小组
which is part of the W3C.
这是W3C工作的一部分
And they show checklist of accessibility features
它们展示了无障碍特性要求的清单
that can or must be implemented
那些可以或者必须实施
to meet certain accessibility standards,
为了满足某些无障碍标准要求
and give you guidelines on how to pursue them.
并为你提供如何实现这些要求的指导
And the important thing is that these are pursued, again,
重要的是，我们要再次致力于实现这些
by a diverse group of internal and external stakeholders
由不同的内部和外部利益相关者
with and without disabilities. 114-p
其中有残障人士和无残障人士 114-p
Now, this is an example of an accessibility audit.
现在，这是一个无障碍审计的示例
So companies should audit their accessibility capabilities
因此，公司应该审核其无障碍的特性要求
from time to time, you know, quarterly,
时不时的，每个季度
or at least semi-annually to see how things are progressing.
或者至少每半年一次，看看事情进展如何
And it is not a one-and-done effort,
这不是一个一次性的工作
but should be a sustained ongoing effort
却应该是一项持续不断的努力
that represents a longterm commitment. slide-6
是一项长期的任务 slide-7
I encourage you as often as you can,
我鼓励你们尽可能多地
to look at developer programs
看一下开发者的项目
and explore their sections that deal with accessibility,
并研究他们关于无障碍开发的部分
and also to check out the many web resources
还可以看看许多的 web 资源
that help you keep on top of what's new and what's next
这有助于你掌握最新动态和下一步计划
in the world of accessibility. 127-p
在无障碍的世界里 127-p
They fall into a couple of categories.
它们可以分为几类
Corporate accessibility websites,
企业无障碍网站
usually if you type in the URL of a tech company,
通常，如果你输入一家科技公司的URL
you type /accessibility,
你可以输入/无障碍
you'll be taken to a developer website that shows tools
你会看到显示工具的开发者网站
and how to get help and ask questions
以及如何获得帮助和提出问题
and shows you accessibility success stories. 134-p
并向你展示有关无障碍的成功案例 134-p
Next are communities of practice like the IAAP,
其次是像 IAAP 这样的实践社区
the International Association
国际协会
of Accessibility Professionals,
无障碍专业人士的
and WebAIM, which stands for Web Access In Mind. 138-p
还有 WebAIM，意思是着 Web Access In Mind 138-p
There are also very good courses offered by schools,
学校也会提供非常好的课程
and a good place to look for them
而且是一个研究它们的好地方
is Coursera and also Skillshare.
是 Coursera，还有 Skillshare
They have courses ranging from introductions
他们有从入门介绍的课程
to accessibility program on the web
到在 web 上创建无障碍程序
to building accessibility teams in your companies. 144-p
到在你的公司创建无障碍团队 144-p
And the fourth category are accessibility consultancies.
第四类是无障碍咨询
They offer, they do a lot of content creation
他们提供，他们做了大量的内容创作
and have webinars on accessibility topics.
并举办关于无障碍话题的网络研讨会
But be mindful, one of their main objectives
但要注意，这是他们的主要目的之一
is to send a bot to your website
是向你的网站发送一个 bot
to search for accessibility defects
去检索无障碍缺陷
and then sell you consulting services.
然后向你提供咨询服务
And that's no substitute for an accessibility program
这并不能替代一个无障碍项目
at your company that's fully resourced
在你的公司里，有充足资源的
and designed for the longterm. slide-7
长期设计的项目 slide-8
So why are we so interested in accessibility?
那么为什么我们对无障碍感兴趣呢
Well, I think the WCAG expresses it in the right way.
嗯，我认为WCAG用正确的方式告诉我们
They say that they want just to make interfaces
他们说他们只想实现端口
that are perceivable, operable and understandable
可感知、可操作和可理解的
by the widest possible range of users.
有尽可能广泛的用户使用
And also robust, so they stand up to and take advantage
而且也很强大，所以他们定位在，并利用
of platforms and operating systems
平台和操作系统
as they evolve from time to time. 162-p
随着时间的推移自身演变 162-p
This involves a commitment to universal design,
这涉及到对通用设计的操作命令
again, one version of the app for everyone,
再说一次，一个为所有人设计的的应用程序版本
not different versions
不是另一个版本
for different disabled subpopulations. 166-p
特别针对残障人士亚群体。 166-p
It involves us creating experiences that are customizable
它关系到我们为最终用户创建可定制化的体验
by end-users 'cause not all people are cognitively disabled
因为不是所有人都以相同的方式有认知障碍
or blind or hearing-impaired in the same manner. 169-p
失明或听力受损 169-p
So you want things to be able to be tailored
所以你希望事情能够量身定做
and you want to, again, involve a diverse community
你还想，在说一次，让一个多元化的群体参与进来
of internal and external stakeholders,
内部和外部利益相关者，
so you can get to the right sweet spot of issues
这样你就可以找到问题的关键点
and address the issues
并解决这些问题
that solve problems the most meaningfully. 175-p
最有意义地解决问题 175-p
If we do this, we'll be doing a great service.
如果我们这样做，我们在做一项很好的服务
And then I encourage you to find people you love
然后我鼓励你找到你爱的人
with disabilities and people in your community,
残障人士，和你们社区的人
and lead them to these accessibility innovations
并引导他们实现这些无障碍创新
and teach them what's going on.
告诉他们去怎么做
Because I guarantee you that not all disabled people
因为我确信，不是所有的残障人士
are as capable or as willing
有能力或愿意去
to discover accessible innovations as we might think. 183-p
如我们猜想，去探索无障碍方面的创新 183-p
And so if we do that, we'll be doing a great service.
因此，如果我们这样做，我们在进行一项伟大的服务
And again, we're part of the media creation business.
再说一次，我们是媒体创作业务的一部分
And I think that it's a wonderful thing we're doing
我认为这是我们正在做的一件很棒的事情
to involve more and more people
让越来越多的人参与进来
in the use of our creation tools, and creating goodwill
来使用我们的创作工具，营造好的商誉
and building our reputations and brands
以及建立我们的声誉和品牌
and building better products for everyone. slide-8
为每个人打造更好的产品 slide-9
So let me wrap it all up with a treat for you.
最后，请让我介绍一个人给大家，以此来结束这个演讲
This is Jason Dasent,
这是 Jason Dasent
he's the owner of Overdrive Recording in Trinidad.
他是在Trinidad 的 Overdrive Recording 的老板。
He is a key advisor and consultant to Avid
他是 Avid 的重要顾问和咨询专家
and other companies on accessibility.
还有其他的无障碍公司
He is completely blind.
他完全失明
So here he is working on some Caribbean music tracks
这里，他正在制作一些加勒比音乐歌曲
independently and without sighted assistance. 198-p
独自，并且在没有正常视力的人的帮助下 198-p
We owe him a great deal.
我们欠他的太多
You can see that he moves through Pro Tools
大家可以看到他使用Pro Tools
and other products with the same speed and facility,
以及其他具有相同速度和设施的产品
as people with normal eyesight.
对正常视力的人
And it's the same version of Pro Tools
这是同一版本的 Pro Tools
that the sighted users have. 204-p
正常视力的用户有的 204-p
(upbeat reggae music) 205-p
（欢快的雷鬼音乐） 205-p
Hey guys, I'm Jay,
嘿，大家好，我是Jay，
a producer from Trinidad in the Caribbean,
来自 Caribbean Trinidad 的制片人
currently based here in the UK.
目前在英国
And today's a really special day.
今天是非常特别的一天
I'm getting to hang out with Avid, right,
我要和 Avid 出去玩了，对吧
my friends at Avid, talking about the Carbon
我的在 Avid 的朋友们，谈论 Carbon
and the Vintage Organ plugins
还有老式的风琴配件
that comes with it from Native Instruments. 213-p
它来自于 Native Instruments。 213-p
Okay, so nothing is quantized or anything yet, right?
好吧，因此没有什么是可以数字化的，或者别的什么，对吧
I'll do it after, because I just want to go
我之后再去做，因为我想去
like on the spur of the moment, whatever I'm feeling,
就像一时冲动，不管我感觉如何
we can definitely clean it up after. 217-p
我们之后一定会把它清理干净 217-p
But that's the organ and some drums.
但那是风琴和鼓
Let's get a bassline.
我们来个低音
Let's hit record and see what it gives. 220-p
让我们打开唱片，看看它能带来什么 220-p
(metronome starts) 221-p
（节奏开始） 221-p
(Jason playing upbeat reggae music) 222-p
（Jason 演奏着欢快的雷鬼音乐） 222-p
Well, I sure appreciate your time, slide-10
嗯，我很感谢大家抽出时间来 slide-10
and I hope you enjoyed this talk.
我希望你喜欢这次演讲
If you have any questions about this document
如果大家对这个演讲内容有任何问题
or the work that Avid's doing on accessibility,
或者对 Avid 在无障碍方面所做的工作
or just want to share some cool ideas,
或者只是想分享一些很酷的想法
just write to meet accessibility@avid.com. slide-11
给我写信就行，邮箱地址是 accessibility@avid.com. slide-11
Thank you again.
再次感谢大家